Finding Aid for Stewart F. Hicks papers, 1931-1933
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Stewart F. Hicks papers 1924-1934 1931-1933
Hicks, Stewart F.
1.0 linear foot
2015016 Aa 2; UAl; AC
Stewart F. Hicks graduated from the University of Michigan with a Bachelor of Science in Civil Engineering in 1927 and worked as an engineer for the Michigan State Highway Department on bridge construction projects. The Stewart F. Hicks papers primarily document Hicks's work as a bridge project engineer during the construction of the Manistee Memorial Bridge as well as academic pursuits and early professional work.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Donated by Robert W. Green (donor no. 11132 ) in June, 2014.
No further additions to the collection are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Stewart F. Hicks graduated from the University of Michigan with a Bachelor of Science in Civil Engineering in 1927 and later earned his Master of Science from the University in 1936. His early professional work included working as an assistant to the Village Manager of the Village of Plymouth before he began working for the Michigan State Highway Department as an engineer in charge of bridge construction projects in the 1930s. Hicks worked as a bridge project engineer on a number of bridges, including the Manistee Memorial Bridge.
The collection is organized into two series: Academic and Professional Records and Manistee Memorial Bridge.
The Stewart F. Hicks papers document Hicks' professional career as an engineer. The collection includes some materials related to his academic pursuits and early professional work, but the bulk of the collection relates to Hicks' work as a bridge project engineer on the Manistee Memorial Bridge. Materials relating to the Manistee Memorial Bridge project include correspondence to and from Hicks, daily reports prepared by Hicks, and project files including proposals, charts, blueprints, reports, and news regarding the bridge's dedication.
Subjects:
Bridges--Michigan.; Bridges--Design and construction--Michigan.; Civil engineering.; Engineers--Michigan.; Hicks, Stewart F.; Manistee (Mich.); Michigan. State Highway Department.; University of Michigan. College of Engineering.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Bridge construction--Michigan.; persname
Genre Terms:
Maps.; Photograph albums.; Photographs.
- Academic and Professional Records
  The Academic and Professional Records series (1924-1933, 0.25 linear feet, 1 oversize volume, and 1 oversize folder) consists of a notebook, correspondence, a drawing, a scrapbook containing photographs, reference booklets, and maps detailing Hicks's early academic and professional career.
  - Academic
    - University of Michigan Department of Geodesy and Surveying, Surveying Notes, 1924-1925 (Box 1)
  - Professional
    - Assistant to the Village Manager of Plymouth, Letter of Appointment, 1928 (Box 1)
    - Drawing, Plan of Extra Slab for AB1 of 63-20-12 C-2, 1930 (Box 1)
    - Photo Album, Photographs of Bridge Projects, 1930-1933 (Volume 1)
    - Reference Files
      - "Regulations and Requirements for Laying Out, Platting and Subdividing of Land in the County of Wayne, State of Michigan," 1925 (Box 1)
      - Michigan State Highway Department, "Standard Road and Bridge Specifications," 1926 (Box 1)
      - Michigan State Highway Department, County Road Maps (Box 1)
      - Carnegie Steel Sheet Piling, 1931 (Box 1)
    - Maps
      - Michigan State Highway Department, "Official Michigan Service Map," 1931 (Folder 1)
      - Michigan State Highway Department, "Official Michigan Service Map," 1932 (Folder 1)
      - Michigan County Road Map (Folder 1)
- Manistee Memorial Bridge
  The Manistee Memorial Bridge series (1931-1934, 0.5 linear feet) comprises the bulk of the collection and contains correspondence, reports, blueprints, charts, and news items related to Hicks's work as bridge project engineer during the construction of the Memorial Bridge on U.S. 31 in Manistee.
  - Personal Files and Reports
    - Correspondence, 1932-1934, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Daily Reports, 1932-1933, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Project Files and Reports
    - Proposal for Bascule Bridge MB1 of 61-6-1 over Manistee River, in Manistee on U.S. 31, 1931 (Box 1)
    - Blueprints (Box 1)
    - Breaker Charts (Box 1)
    - Cement Record (Box 1)
    - Temperature Reports, 1932-1933 (Box 1)
    - Charts for Proportioning Concrete Material, 1932-1933 (Box 1)
    - Bridge Dedication
      - The Manistee News-Advocate, October 1933 (Box 1)
      - Michigan Roads and Airports, Vol. XXX No. 45, November 9, 1933 (Box 1)